<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[GitHub DID]]></title><description><![CDATA[GitHub DID is an experimental tool for developing and testing the Decentralized Identity, Credentials, Signature Suites and related Cryptography.]]></description><link>https://docs.github-did.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 02:51:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[V2... Even More Centralized]]></title><description><![CDATA[We’ve done a major rewrite in an attempt to simplify the setup process, and clarify how centralized and dependant on GitHub this method…]]></description><link>https://docs.github-did.com//v2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://docs.github-did.com//v2/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We’ve done a major rewrite in an attempt to simplify the setup process, and clarify how centralized and dependant on GitHub this method really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, there has been a lot of discussion regarding centralization and the DID spec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/w3c-ccg/did-wg-charter/issues/16&quot;&gt;General: current language precludes DIDs/methods leased from an authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/w3c-ccg/did-wg-charter/issues/22&quot;&gt;Decentralized Identifier: “Decentralized” in working group name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stories.jolocom.com/prioritizing-individual-sovereignty-over-interoperability-95ec17a36c9b&quot;&gt;Prioritizing Individual Sovereignty over Interoperability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub DID method should be used mostly for testing and development, and its risks, tradeoffs and implementation details must be clearly communicated to users, and to put an even finer point on it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub DID is centralized, github.com is the root of trust, and repo permissions MUST be considered when deciding whether a DID Document should be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, git has a lot of nice features that are in the family of features used to build truley decentralized identifiers, and there is a lot of interesting work around git    (small g… the software) / git-like protocols and DIDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/Azure-Active-Directory-Identity/Toward-scalable-decentralized-identifier-systems/ba-p/560168&quot;&gt;Toward scalable decentralized identifier systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://continuations.com/post/131622514215/why-decentralized-identity-matters-githubs&quot;&gt;Why Decentralized Identity Matters: Github’s Identity Innovation and Shortcoming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Whats new in “v2”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no official release yet… &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;New DID format: did:github:USERNAME&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We opted to abandon complicated identifier creation in favor of directly relying on the github username and repo. This means less DIDs, but much simpler resolver, and much more user friendly identifiers. We think its worth it for now, and we can add more complex options later if more people are interested in contributing or using GitHub DID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that we also changed the format of the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;didToDIDDocumentURL&lt;/code&gt; function, which converts a “did” to a URL to a JSON-LD Document on github.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new format is: &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;https://github.com/OR13/ghdid/blob/master/index.jsonld&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We “did” this because it unlikely to conflict with any existing repo, and we thought it might be cool to link the cli binary &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;ghdid&lt;/code&gt; to the repo that a user uses to store their GitHub DID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hate this idea, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/decentralized-identity/github-did/issues/new&quot;&gt;please open an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also updated the wallet demo, used for sign, verify, encrypt and decrypt with a proposed OpenPGP Signature Suite. If you are interested in helping develop the signature suite used in these demos, please consider contributing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/w3c-ccg/community/issues/71&quot;&gt;W3C OpenPgpSignature2019 Proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/transmute-industries/PROPOSAL-OpenPgpSignature2019&quot;&gt;OpenPgpSignature2019 JS Implementation and Spec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next steps?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;GitHub API Integration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provide a REST API which can be used to resolve GitHub DIDs, but we’d like to integrate GitHub APIs and provide a more managed easier to use experience. This would also give us a chance to experiment with GitHub OAuth and GitHub DID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;RSA / ECC Signature Suite Demos&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to add some other key types to support interoperability with other DID Methods, especially ones that use &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;secp256k1&lt;/code&gt; curve, used by Bitcoin and Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Moving to DIF]]></title><description><![CDATA[We’re moving GitHub DID to the  DIF ! New Repo URL]]></description><link>https://docs.github-did.com//moving-to-dif/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://docs.github-did.com//moving-to-dif/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We’re moving GitHub DID to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://identity.foundation/&quot;&gt;DIF&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/decentralized-identity/github-did&quot;&gt;New Repo URL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Getting Started]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this tutorial, we’ll walk you through how GitHub DID works. DID Method At the core a DID is the  . its the process that helps resolve the…]]></description><link>https://docs.github-did.com//getting-started/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://docs.github-did.com//getting-started/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we’ll walk you through how GitHub DID works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DID Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the core a DID is the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;method&lt;/code&gt;. its the process that helps resolve the identifier that looks like &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;did:method:123&lt;/code&gt; to the document which is JSON-LD and contains the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;publicKey&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;service&lt;/code&gt; properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub DID is experimental and supports a couple different formats for methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Username DIDs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They look like this (Case Sensitive): &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;did:github:OR13&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resolver knows to convert this string to this url: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OR13/ghdid/master/index.jsonld&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So long as &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;index.jsonld&lt;/code&gt; is a properly formatted DID Document, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;did:github:OR13&lt;/code&gt; is a valid DID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Managing DID Documents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DID Documents can be signed with a &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;proof&lt;/code&gt; property or not. The keys and services listed are up the the controller, and you can create a DID Document simply by copying one of the examples above and updating the id property and keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire security of this method relies on Github. Obviously, Github can censor, revoke, tamper or delete DIDs, which makes this method a “Centralized DID” or “Weak DID”, the terminology is still evolving, you can see a healthy debate &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/w3c-ccg/did-wg-charter/issues/22&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Managing Keys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private keys associated with public keys listed in a document can be managed by various methods including, GPG, custom wallet systems, vaults or cloud based key management systems. Its obviously critical that private keys remain private, and that public keys are revoked (removed from documents), if private keys are compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now understand how to create a GitHub DID, using Github.com’s built in UI and the examples provided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn how to use github-did’s custom test wallet and cli to manage keys, and create documents, head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;/using-the-cli/&quot;&gt;using the cli&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Using the ghdid cli]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this tutorial, we’ll walk you through how to set up a GitHub DID using the CLI and a local wallet to manage keys. See the @github-did/cli…]]></description><link>https://docs.github-did.com//using-the-cli/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://docs.github-did.com//using-the-cli/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we’ll walk you through how to set up a GitHub DID using the CLI and a local wallet to manage keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/decentralized-identity/github-did/tree/master/packages/cli#github-didcli&quot;&gt;See the @github-did/cli tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have used the CLI to setup your DID, you are ready to try out the progressive web app demo, and use your web wallet and linked keys to sign, verify, encrypt and decrypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github-did.com/wallet&quot;&gt;https://github-did.com/wallet&lt;/a&gt; and import your wallet by following the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats! You should now have a usable / resolvable DID to experiment with!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[This GitHub DID documentation website is build with  Gatsby.js . Its mostly just Markdown, GraphQL and React.  Our hope is that its ease of…]]></description><link>https://docs.github-did.com//hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://docs.github-did.com//hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This GitHub DID documentation website is build with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;Gatsby.js&lt;/a&gt;. Its mostly just Markdown, GraphQL and React. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our hope is that its ease of use will encourage contributions.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>